Register of the Committee for the Free World records
Hoover Institution Archives
Committee for the Free World records
1980-1991
89007
Hoover Institution Archives
89 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 5 card file boxes (38.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, conference proceedings, bulletins, press releases, financial records, booklets, phonotapes, and videotapes, relating to American foreign and domestic policy, the moral and intellectual climate in the Western world, relations between the United States and Europe and the Soviet Union, and international communism and anti-communist movements.
Committee for the Free World
Access
Collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1989.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, conference proceedings, bulletins, press releases, financial records, booklets, phonotapes, and videotapes, relating to American foreign and domestic policy, the moral and intellectual climate in the Western world, relations between the United States and Europe and the Soviet Union, and international communism and anti-communist movements.
Historical Note
International anti-communist organization advocating defense of Western values and freedom.
Anti-communist movements.; Communism.; Europe--Intellectual life.; Europe.; Phonotapes.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union.; United States--Civilization--1970-; United States--Foreign relations--1981-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--Europe.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Intellectual life--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.; United States--Politics and government.; Video tapes.
- CORRESPONDENCE/SUBJECT FILES, 1980-1986
  - A (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Elliott
  - Academic Council for Peace and Freedom
  - Allen, Richard V.
  - Arnold, David Brooks
  - B
  - Balch, Stephen H. (Box 2)
  - Brady, William H.
  - Brazil
  - C
  - Committee for the Free World (U.K.)
  - D
  - Davis, Shelby Cullom
  - Delfiner, Henry
  - E
  - F
  - Feulner, Edwin, J., Jr.
  - Fuller, Henry R.
  - Gavrin, Irving (Box 3)
  - Godson, Roy
  - Gold, Philip
  - Goldberg, Gerhard Wolfgang
  - Goldman, Andrew
  - Goldstein, Stanley
  - H
  - Henze, Paul B.
  - Howe, E. L.
  - I
  - J
  - Joyce, Michael S.
  - K (Box 4)
  - KGB Connection
  - Kaplan, Roger F.
  - Krakowski, Elie D.
  - Kristol, Irving
  - Krygier, Richard
  - Krynski, John
  - L (Box 5)
  - Labedz, Leopold
  - Larry, Richard M.
  - Lefever, Ernest W.
  - Lenkowsky, Leslie
  - Lucentini, Mauro
  - Lyons, James E.
  - M
  - McDonald, Micharl P. (Box 6)
  - Marcus, Daniel J.
  - Marcus, Philip N.
  - Medecins sans Frontieres
  - Meira Penna, J. O. de
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo
  - Miller, James A.
  - Morrison, Micah
  - Mullin, Victoria
  - N
  - Nicaraguan Freedom Fund
  - O
  - Orwell Review
  - Outreach
  - P
  - Podhoretz, Norman (Box 7)
  - Poland, Conference on, 1981
  - PRODEMCA
  - Prybyla, Jan S.
  - Q
  - R
  - Rebelo, Jose C.
  - Richardson, R. Randolph
  - Rumsfeld, Donald
  - S
  - S (Box 8)
  - Sanders, Sol W.
  - Schimel, David
  - Seggerman, Harry G. A.
  - Shube, Sam
  - Siegelman, Philip
  - Singer, Max
  - Skacel, Milan B.
  - Sontag, Erich H.
  - Student activity
  - Students for Peace and Security
  - Swan, John L. (Box 9)
  - T
  - Tismaneanu, Vladimir
  - Train, John
  - Tyrrell, R. Emmett, Jr.
  - U
  - V
  - Box 10 W
  - Weeks, Albert L.
  - Weigel, George S., Jr.
  - Wheldon, Jacqueline
  - Wick, Charles Z.
  - Windon, Bernard M.
  - Winston, Emanuel A.
  - Wohlstetter, John C. (Box 11)
  - Women and Families for Defence
  - Wright, Elizabeth
  - Wynne, Edward
  - Y
  - Young Professionals Program
  - Z
- CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS
  - Trans-Atlantic Crisis, Conference on, Phonotape cassette recordings of proceedings, 1982. (Box 11)
  - Our Country and Our Culture, Conference on, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Phonotape cassette recordings of proceedings
    - Galleys of proceedings
    - Transcripts of proceedings
    - Transcripts of proceedings (Box 13)
  - The State of the Nation, Conference on, 1984
    - Transcripts of proceedings (Box 14)
    - Transcripts of proceedings (Box 15)
    - Photographs of proceedings
    - Phonotape cassette recordings of proceedings
  - Thinking about East/West, Conference on, 1985
    - Phonotape cassette recordings of proceedings (Box 16)
    - Transcripts of proceedings
    - Transcripts of proceedings (Box 17)
    - Galleys of proceedings
    - Printed copy of proceedings
- CONTENTIONS (Bulletin of the Committee for the Free World)
  - Printed copies (Box 18)
    - 1981-1985
    - 1986-1988 (Box 19)
  - Working materials for issues (Box 20)
    - 1982 June-1984 October
    - 1984 November-1985 October (Box 21)
    - 1985 November-1986 May (Box 22)
    - 1986 June-October (Box 23)
    - 1986 November-December (Box 24)
    - Drafts of undated articles
- MISCELLANY
  - Press releases (Box 25)
  - Press clips
  - Brochures
  - Name and address printout
  - Financial statements
  - Booklets published by the Committee for the Free World
  - Videotapes (Box 26)
    - Agents of Deception
    - The KGB Connection
- CONTENTIONS, 1987-1990
  Scope and Contents note
  Printed copies and working materials for issues.
  - January-April, 1987 (Box 27)
  - May-August, 1987 (Box 28)
  - September-December, 1987 (Box 29)
  - January-April, 1988 (Box 30)
  - May-August, 1988 (Box 31)
  - September-December, 1988 (Box 32)
  - January-April, 1989 (Box 33)
  - May-August, 1989 (Box 34)
  - September-December, 1989 (Box 35)
  - January-April, 1990 (Box 35)
  - May-December, includes subject index, 1990 (Box 36)
- DOCUMENTS RELATING TO THE FOUNDING AND OPERATIONS OF THE COMMITTEE FOR THE FREE WORLD, 1981-1990
  - 1981-1983 (Box 37)
  - 1984-1988 (Box 38)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 39)
- CORRESPONDENCE/SUBJECT FILES, 1980-1990
  - A (Box 39)
  - B-Conn (Box 40)
  - Cont-F (Box 41)
  - G-Ha (Box 42)
  - He-K (Box 43)
  - L-Ne (Box 44)
  - Ni-Si (Box 45)
  - Sk-Z (Box 46)
- CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS, 1981-1990
  Includes phonotape cassettes.
  - 1981-1986 (Box 47)
  - 1987 (Boxes 48-50)
  - 1988 (Boxes 51-53)
  - Does "The West" Still Exist? published conference proceedings, 1990 (Box 54)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1980-1990 (Boxes 55-90)
- Not yet described. (Boxes 91-97)
- Sound Cassettes (Box 98)
  Contains cassettes originally housed in boxes 11, 47, 48, 51, and 54.